<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Alizila</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.alizila.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.alizila.com/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 11:08:58 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
	<item>
		<title>News Roundup: 11.11 Updates on Comprehensive Consumption, AI Innovation, New Brand Champions, and Amap’s Partnership with XPeng</title>
		<link>https://www.alizila.com/news-roundup-11-11-updates-on-comprehensive-consumption-ai-innovation-new-brand-champions-and-amaps-partnership-with-xpeng/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ivy Ke]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 09:02:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[11.11]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News Roundup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[11.11 Global Shopping Festival]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tmall]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.alizila.com/?p=65964</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As this year&#8217;s 11.11 Shopping Festival hits its stride, this week&#8217;s news roundup spotlights how innovation is helping brands and merchants gain a competitive edge. Alibaba’s strategy to build a comprehensive consumption platform is unlocking cross-selling opportunities and deepening customer engagement. Across the ecosystem, AI tools are being deployed at scale to enhance operations, marketing, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>As this year&#8217;s 11.11 Shopping Festival hits its stride, this week&#8217;s news roundup spotlights how innovation is helping brands and merchants gain a competitive edge. Alibaba’s strategy to build a comprehensive consumption platform is unlocking cross-selling opportunities and deepening customer engagement. Across the ecosystem, AI tools are being deployed at scale to enhance operations, marketing, search, and customer services. Beyond e-commerce, Amap has formed a strategic partnership with XPeng, advancing progress in autonomous driving.</p>



<p><strong>Comprehensive Consumption Platform Strengthens Cross-Selling and Customer Loyalty</strong></p>



<p>This year’s 11.11 campaign has showcased the power of synergies across Alibaba’s consumption platforms, driving effective cross-selling from the larger consumer base.</p>



<p>As of November 4, new users gained through Taobao Instant Commerce – the platform’s quick commerce channel – have placed over 100 million e-commerce orders on Taobao and Tmall.</p>



<p>Within the Taobao Instant Commerce channel, approximately 20,000 food and beverage brands and more than 860 non-food brands and merchants have doubled their average daily sales compared to September levels, highlighting the strong growth potential of the integrated ecosystem.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" width="1200" height="800" src="https://alizila.oss-us-west-1.aliyuncs.com/uploads/2025/11/ALEX7607-opq4047683823.jpg" alt="Alex7607 Opq4047683823" class="wp-image-65965"/></figure>



<p>High-spending purchasers continue to drive the campaign’s momentum. 88VIP members have contributed more than 70% of GMV for leading brands since the start of 11.11, with daily active buyers among 88VIP members up 39% year-over-year.</p>



<p>Meanwhile, Taobao’s tiered cross-platform loyalty program, launched in August, has seen its top three tiers &#8211; Platinum, Diamond, and Black Diamond – surpass 100 million members who shop more than 90 days per year over average, underscoring their purchasing power and brand affinity.</p>



<p><strong>AI at Scale: How Technology is Powering 11.11</strong></p>



<p>This year marks the first <a href="https://www.alizila.com/ai-powers-1111/">11.11 where generative AI has been deployed at scale</a> across the Alibaba ecosystem. Merchants and consumers on Taobao and Tmall are already seeing tangible benefits.</p>



<p>The <em>AI Business Advisor</em> tool has generated over five million analytical reports since October, helping merchants prepare for and manage the campaign. Surveys indicate the tool has reduced merchant workloads by 30% and boosted operational efficiency by 150%.</p>



<p>To support marketing and creative production, Alibaba’s AI-Generated Content (AIGC) suite has enabled merchants to produce over 150 million visual assets since October, resulting in double-digit increases in clicks during A/B testing.</p>



<p>Consumers are also benefitting from AI-powered support. <em>Dianxiaomi</em>, the intelligent customer service assistant for Taobao and Tmall, handled 300 million queries during this 11.11 period. Merchants using AI-aided service tools have seen conversion rates rise 30% year-over-year.</p>



<p><strong>New Brands Shine with Distinctive Offerings</strong></p>



<p>New and emerging brands continue to make their mark during 11.11, appealing to consumers with distinctive, personalized products that transform niche interests into mainstream lifestyles &#8211; from affordable smart telescopes for astronomy enthusiasts to customizable keyboards for tech lovers.</p>



<p>Since the start of the campaign, 302 brands launched on Tmall within the past five years have topped their sub-categories. The mother-and-baby sector led with 37 new champions, while sports &amp; outdoor and home improvement categories each recorded 31.</p>



<p>In total, 14 newcomers have already surpassed RMB100 million in sales, while 133 brands surpassed RMB 10 million. Top performers include pet food producer ROSY FRESH, high-speed dryer brand Laifen and 3D printer maker Bambu Lab.</p>



<p><strong>Amap and XPeng Partner on Robotaxi Expansion</strong></p>



<p>On Wednesday, Alibaba’s Amap announced a strategic partnership with XPeng Motors to accelerate the rollout of XPeng’s robotaxi services, marking a major milestone following Amap’s <a href="https://www.alizila.com/amap-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">AI upgrade</a> in August.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" width="1200" height="675" src="https://alizila.oss-us-west-1.aliyuncs.com/uploads/2025/11/Amap-x-XPeng.png" alt="Amap X Xpeng" class="wp-image-65966"/></figure>



<p>Under the agreement, Amap will integrate XPeng robotaxi services into its ride-hailing platform, expanding service coverage and supporting XPeng’s global expansion.</p>



<p>This partnership follows similar integrations by other Chinese players — including WeRide and Pony.ai – and reflects the growing momentum in China’s autonomous driving sector.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>L’Oréal China and Alibaba Cloud Announce Full-Stack AI Collaboration to Accelerate Beauty Innovation and Efficiency</title>
		<link>https://www.alizila.com/loreal-china-and-alibaba-cloud-announce-full-stack-ai-collaboration-to-accelerate-beauty-innovation-and-efficiency/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Gabbie Fu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 09:45:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Company News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alibaba]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alibaba Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Beauty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chinese Consumers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cloud Computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[collaboration]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.alizila.com/?p=65959</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[
• Alibaba Cloud's AI capabilities to enhance consumer experience and transform the beauty industry 
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>L’Oréal China and Alibaba Cloud, the digital technology and intelligence backbone of Alibaba Group, announced a strategic collaboration to deploy AI capability across multiple business scenarios, including intelligent customer service, and AI agents. Leveraging Alibaba Cloud’s advanced infrastructure and AI capabilities, the collaboration aims to boost operational efficiency, elevate consumer experiences, and advance technological innovation across the beauty industry.</p>



<p>Drawing on Alibaba Cloud&#8217; AI model capabilities, L’Oréal China has developed an agentic application powered by a comprehensive domain knowledge base—to deliver accurate, intelligent Q&amp;A for frontline skincare practitioners and improve communication efficiency with consumers. In addition, L’Oréal China’s IT organization is adopting Alibaba Cloud’s AI coding assistant, to accelerate software development.</p>



<p>Under the collaboration, L’Oréal China will build, fine-tune, and deploy model applications on Alibaba Cloud&#8217;s AI models and Model Studio, Alibaba Cloud&#8217;s one-stop AI development platform to accelerate the business delivery.</p>



<p>Additionally, Alibaba Cloud will provide a comprehensive AI training and certification program to help L’Oréal China teams rapidly build AI literacy and application skills, supporting a more creative, future-ready organization.</p>



<p><strong>Barbara Lavernos, Deputy Chief Executive Officer L’Oreal Group, in charge of Research, Innovation and Technology </strong>said: “We firmly believe that the future of beauty lies at the intersection of technology, science, and creativity. China’s fast-evolving consumer landscape, and increasingly discerning consumer sentiment offer a uniquely fertile ground for Beauty Tech innovation. Our collaboration with Alibaba Cloud embodies this spirit of co-creation, and together, we aim to elevate consumer experiences, boost operational efficiency, and set a new benchmark for sustainable and responsible Beauty Tech.”</p>



<p><strong>Patrick LIU, President of Public Cloud Business and Senior Vice President of&nbsp;Alibaba Cloud&nbsp;Intelligence</strong> said: “The beauty industry is an ideal arena for the large-scale application of AI. We’re honored to collaborate with L’Oréal, the global beauty leader, on a full-stack AI collaboration. Together with L’Oréal China, we’ll explore AI innovations in marketing content and consumer insights—accelerating their digital transformation and setting a benchmark for the consumer goods industry.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Alibaba Celebrates 100-day Countdown to Milano Cortina 2026 with Exclusive Olympic Merchandise Launch in China</title>
		<link>https://www.alizila.com/alibaba-celebrates-100-day-countdown-to-milano-cortina-2026-with-exclusive-olympic-merchandise-launch-in-china/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Gabbie Fu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 06:15:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[11.11]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alibaba Group]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[11.11 Global Shopping Festival]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alibaba]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[E-Commerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Olympics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tmall]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.alizila.com/?p=65931</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Alibaba&#160;has kicked off its 100-day countdown to the&#160;Olympic Winter Games Milano Cortina 2026&#160;with a bang, unveiling a fresh collection of official Olympic merchandise on Tmall just as the annual 11.11 Global Shopping Festival gets underway. In collaboration with the International Olympic Committee (IOC), Alibaba has unveiled a new range of official products featuring Tina and [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><a href="https://www.olympics.com/ioc/partners/alibaba">Alibaba</a>&nbsp;has kicked off its 100-day countdown to the&nbsp;<a href="https://olympics.com/ioc/milano-cortina-2026">Olympic Winter Games Milano Cortina 2026</a>&nbsp;with a bang, unveiling a fresh collection of official Olympic merchandise on Tmall just as the annual 11.11 Global Shopping Festival gets underway.</p>



<p>In collaboration with the International Olympic Committee (IOC), Alibaba has unveiled a new range of official products featuring Tina and Milo, the mascots of the Olympic and Paralympic Winter Games Milano Cortina 2026, as well as the first official Olympic jewellery collection for the Chinese market. The announcement was made during the Tmall 11.11 Super Launch event at the West Bund Dome Art Centre in Shanghai.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" width="1200" height="800" src="https://alizila.oss-us-west-1.aliyuncs.com/uploads/2025/10/lQDPJxTD2DFkE-_NDOHNE1KwHQiHuhN94LQI3mIKSVHsAA_4946_3297.jpg" alt="Lqdpjxtd2dfke Ndohne1kwhqihuhn94lqi3miksvhsaa 4946 3297" class="wp-image-65933" /></figure>



<p>“With 100 days to go to the Olympic Winter Games, this is the perfect moment to introduce these new items to fans, including the first official Olympic jewellery collection, available exclusively in China. We are especially pleased that this launch forms part of Tmall’s Double 11 – the world’s largest online shopping festival.” Said <strong>Anne-Sophie Voumard </strong><strong>Managing Director of IOC Television and Marketing Services.</strong></p>



<p>Attending the event on behalf of the IOC, <strong>Betty Aldini, Head of Licensing, E-commerce and Merchandising</strong> said “On behalf of the International Olympic Committee, I would like to thank Tmall for your continued support. You have played a key role in helping fans access official Olympic products and connect with the Games in meaningful ways.”</p>



<p><strong>Liu Bo, President of Tmall, Alibaba Group</strong>, said: “Joining hands with the IOC, we&#8217;re thrilled to officially debut the Tina and Milo mascot collections and the IOC&#8217;s first Olympic jewellery line exclusively on Tmall &#8216;s Olympic Flagship Store during Tmall Double 11 Super Launch, kicking off our journey toward Milano Cortina 2026. By bringing the new collections of products, we aim to make official Olympic merchandise easy to discover, fun to experience, and trusted to buy, helping fans across China connect with the spirit of the Olympic Games ahead of the Winter Olympics.”</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" width="1200" height="800" src="https://alizila.oss-us-west-1.aliyuncs.com/uploads/2025/10/lQDPKGtkbGfkIT_ND6HNF3CwPu5DExkC5LEI3RCtzI5DAA_6000_4001.jpg" alt="Lqdpkgtkbgfkit Nd6hnf3cwpu5dexkc5lei3rctzi5daa 6000 4001" class="wp-image-65932" /></figure>



<p>The new Milano Cortina 2026 product line features more than 10 mascot-themed items, including plush toys, keychains and figurines, alongside a series of necklaces, earrings and bracelets inspired by the Olympic symbol. The launch event was streamed live on Alibaba’s Taobao Live platform and accompanied by a four-day “Milano Cortina 2026 – Ice and Snow Wonderland” pop-up exhibition at Shanghai’s West Bund Dream Centre, giving visitors a first look at the collection and the opportunity to meet the mascots in person.</p>



<p>To celebrate the milestone, Alibaba’s platforms also hosted a series of Olympic-themed activations. On 29 October, Taobao Live broadcast a special livestream featuring Tina and Milo and unveiled a limited-edition Milano Cortina 2026 “creative hourglass” collectible. Meanwhile, Alibaba’s Hangzhou Xixi campus has been transformed with large mascot installations and Olympic-themed displays.</p>



<p>In addition, AliExpress will support the Milano Cortina 2026 Organising Committee’s ticketing promotion by offering benefits to AliExpress Saver members purchasing tickets for the upcoming Games.</p>



<p>Since becoming a Worldwide Olympic Partner in 2017, Alibaba has committed to helping the IOC transform the Olympic Games for the digital era through cloud and e-commerce services. In 2018, the IOC launched the Official Olympic Online Store on Tmall, marking a major milestone in its digital transformation journey.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>News Roundup: 11.11 Brand Performance, Designer Brands Shine, and AI to Combat Extreme Heat </title>
		<link>https://www.alizila.com/news-roundup-11-11-brand-performance-designer-brands-shine-and-ai-to-combat-extreme-heat/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Morgan Lin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 04:12:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[11.11]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News Roundup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sustainability]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.alizila.com/?p=65905</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This article has been updated on October 28 to include the latest sales performance of Taobao Fashion brands. This week, the 2025 11.11 Shopping Festival opened with impressive brand performance, as Taobao and Tmall partnered with merchants to offer&#160;innovative experiences&#160;and consumer benefits. Boutique fashion brands cultivated on Taobao distinguished themselves with original designs, supported by [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><em>This article has been updated on October 28 to include the latest sales performance of Taobao Fashion brands.</em></p>



<p>This week, the 2025 11.11 Shopping Festival opened with impressive brand performance, as Taobao and Tmall partnered with merchants to offer&nbsp;<a href="https://www.alizila.com/ai-powers-1111/">innovative experiences</a>&nbsp;and consumer benefits. Boutique fashion brands cultivated on Taobao distinguished themselves with original designs, supported by the platform’s runway-style livestream show. Beyond e-commerce, Alibaba Cloud also partnered with the Group on Earth Observations and Haina to protect cities from extreme heat.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" width="1200" height="800" src="https://alizila.oss-us-west-1.aliyuncs.com/uploads/2025/10/LOUL4025-opq4031230888-1.jpg" alt="Loul4025 Opq4031230888 (1)" class="wp-image-65915"/></figure>



<p><strong>11.11 Opens with Record-Breaking Momentum</strong></p>



<p>The 11.11 checkout period began at 8 p.m. on October 20, with Taobao and Tmall witnessing impressive brand performance. By 9 p.m., 80 brands surpassed RMB100 million in GMV while over 30,000 brands doubled their first-hour sales&nbsp;, both outpacing last year’s opening results.</p>



<p>Beauty brands drove early momentum. In less than 10 minutes, eight brands crossed RMB100 million. Premium skincare labels SK-II, Clarins, and Clé de Peau Beauté each yielded double-digit growth within the first hour.</p>



<p>Sportswear brands experienced similar success. FILA hit RMB100 million in just 6 minutes, with Nike, Lululemon, adidas, Anta, Camel, and Descente all hitting the milestone within half an hour. Descente, ASICS, and PUMA each recorded double-digit growth in the first hour.</p>



<p>In consumer electronics, Apple’s official Tmall flagship store saw its&nbsp;iPhone sales in the first two hours surpass last year’s entire Day 1 total. Top-performing gadgets – AirPods 4, Apple Watch Series 11, iQOO 15, the Nintendo Switch console, and Xiaomi 17 Pro Max – each crossed RMB 10 million in GMV within an hour.</p>



<p>The festival runs through November 14. Stay tuned for more updates from the 11.11 campaign and check out <a href="https://www.alibabagroup.com/en-US/resource-events">photos </a>from Alibaba’s campus as well as the kickoff event!</p>



<p><strong>Spotlight: Boutique Original Design Brands On the Rise</strong></p>



<p>During the 11.11 kickoff, apparel SMEs focused on original designs, verified under Taobao’s iFASHION label, experienced strong momentum. Their combined sales jumped by 50% in the week of October 20. Five boutique brands achieved over RMB100 million in weekly sales, while nine brands surpassed RMB10 million milestones.</p>



<p>Merchants are increasingly leveraging Taobao’s exclusive livestreaming IP, <em>Super Live</em>, which provides professional production capabilities for fashion show-style runway livestreams. Among them, homegrown brand MSBEAST generated over RMB50 million during its October 20 live session, more than doubling last year’s performance.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" width="1200" height="1200" src="https://alizila.oss-us-west-1.aliyuncs.com/uploads/2025/10/chicjoc-super-live.jpg" alt="Chicjoc Super Live" class="wp-image-65922"/></figure>



<p><a href="https://chicjoc.taobao.com/">CHICJOC</a> , now with physical stores in Los Angeles and Paris, then sets a new record for a single livestream by Chinese apparel brands, with its 30-hour nonstop <em>Super Live </em>Session on October 25 and 26. The brand achieved over RMB100 million in sales, breaking the RMB60 million record it set during last year’s 11.11 Super Live event.</p>



<p>Meanwhile, brand-operated livestreaming continues to expand, with nearly 50 brand-run channels each surpassing RMB10 million in sales during the week of October 20.</p>



<p><strong>Global Collaboration in Harnessing AI to Combat Extreme Heat</strong></p>



<p>By 2050, more than 5 billion people worldwide are projected to face health-threatening extreme heat, with urban populations particularly at risk due to the urban heat island effect. In response to this escalating crisis, United Nations Secretary-General António Guterres has urged immediate action to address extreme heat. To support this call, the Group on Earth Observations (GEO) convened the Global Heat Resilience Service—an initiative designed to empower cities with timely, data-driven insights to mitigate local heat risks.</p>



<p>From 2025 to 2027, the Global Heat Resilience Service will be piloted in cities around the world, reaching an estimated 12 to 20 million people.</p>



<p>Building on this momentum, GEO has recently partnered with Alibaba Cloud and the Shanghai Haina Academy of Engineering (Haina) to accelerate the development and implementation of the Global Heat Resilience Service, leveraging artificial intelligence and advanced technologies to enhance urban climate resilience.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" width="1179" height="788" src="https://alizila.oss-us-west-1.aliyuncs.com/uploads/2025/10/Group-on-Earth-Observations-Alibaba-Cloud-and-Haina-join-forces-to-protect-cities-from-extreme-heat.jpg" alt="Group On Earth Observations, Alibaba Cloud And Haina Join Forces To Protect Cities From Extreme Heat" class="wp-image-65908"/></figure>



<p>The first phase of the collaboration will focus on pilot implementation of the Global Heat Resilience Service in selected cities, beginning with Hangzhou and Shanghai.<br>&nbsp;<br>Using a scenario-based approach, the three parties will integrate data on risk, exposure and vulnerability &#8211; including Earth observation data and Alibaba Cloud&#8217;s urban management capabilities &#8211; to assess and manage heat risks.<br>&nbsp;<br>GEO will specify and coordinate access to diverse datasets spanning environmental, climate, demographic, and socio-economic dimensions for comprehensive risk assessment; Alibaba Cloud will contribute expertise in AI, cloud computing and large-scale analytics; and Haina will co-design a prototype, drawing on its experience in urban digitalisation.<br>&nbsp;<br>Insights, tools and community campaigns developed through pilots in China’s Yangtze River Delta region are expected to inform the expansion of the service to other cities worldwide, particularly those in developing regions with limited access to heat resilience infrastructure.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Alibaba’s Quark Launches AI Chat Assistant, Powered by Qwen Model</title>
		<link>https://www.alizila.com/alibabas-quark-launches-ai-chat-assistant-powered-by-qwen-model/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Gabbie Fu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 06:56:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[11.11]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI Agenda]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alibaba Group]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[11.11 Global Shopping Festival]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quark]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.alizila.com/?p=65896</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Quark AI Glasses joins 11.11 shopping festival to kick off online pre-sale in China starting October 24
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Quark, Alibaba’s flagship consumer-facing AI application has unveiled AI Chat Assistant, a new AI chatbot mode powered by Alibaba’s latest Qwen3 models. Integrated into the Quark app, Quark AI Chat Assistant enables users to switch to a chatbot interface for intelligent conversations via text or voice, accessing real-time information and services smoothly. This marks a new phase of integrated AI that unifies dialogue and search capabilities within a single application. <br><br>With the latest version of the Quark app downloaded for both iOS and Android system, users can switch to Quark AI Chat Assistant mode by choosing “assistant” directly in the Quark AI Super Box or swipe right on the screen for quick access to the chat interface. With the newly added feature, Quark provides a dual engine of AI search and conversation, delivering a complete AI experience that both gets you straight to the information you need and enables deeper exploration.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left"><img decoding="async" width="800" height="800" class="wp-image-65899" style="width: 800px;" src="https://alizila.oss-us-west-1.aliyuncs.com/uploads/2025/10/夸克3.jpg" alt="夸克3"><br><br>Powered by Alibaba’s latest Qwen3 models, Quark’s AI Chat Assistant offers strong reasoning, understanding, and execution capabilities. Beyond intelligent Q&amp;A capabilities, Quark AI Chat Assistant has integrated core functions including deep search, photo-based problem solving, and AI writing, while supporting multimodal interactions such as photo editing, AI camera and phone calls, and save with one click Moving forward, Quark AI Chat Assistant will further integrate various MCP (Model Context Protocol) tools from within the Alibaba ecosystem to continuously enhance its task execution capabilities.<br><br>Alibaba’s Quark AI Glasses Kicks off Online Pre-sale in China Starting October 24th <br><br>Joining 11.11 shopping festival, the world’s largest shopping event, Alibaba’s Quark AI Glasses will start pre-sale at 12:00 AM on October 24th on Alibaba’s e-Commerce platform Tmall. Once orders are placed, Quark will start fulfilling shipments progressively from December onwards.<br><br>Simultaneously the Glasses will open for 1 RMB reservations on China’s major e-Commerce platforms such as JD.com and Douyin, with purchasing available and deliveries commencing in phases starting in early December </p>



<p class="has-text-align-left"><img decoding="async" width="800" height="533" class="wp-image-65900" style="width: 800px;" src="https://alizila.oss-us-west-1.aliyuncs.com/uploads/2025/10/夸克眼镜2.jpg" alt="夸克眼镜2"><br><br>According to the pre-sale page on Tmall platform, the original pre-sale price for Quark AI glasses is RMB 4699. After applying platform coupons, regular consumers will pay RMB 3999 while 88VIP members will pay RMB 3699. Consumers can also choose bundled packages that include accessories like a carrying case and charging adapter. Additionally, buyers can also select customized lenses of varying prices and thicknesses based on their prescription for nearsightedness<br><br>As Alibaba’s first self-developed smart eyewear powered by the Qwen large language model and Quark’s multimodal AI capabilities, Quark AI Glasses were debuted at this year’s World AI Conference in Shanghai. <br><br>Lightweight and ergonomically designed, Quark AI Glasses support hands-free calling, music streaming, real-time language translation, and meeting transcription. The glasses are engineered to deliver smooth AI-enabled interactions, featuring long battery life and high-quality imaging to ensure a premium user experience. <br> <br></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>AI Powers Large-scale Applications at the World’s Largest Shopping Festival</title>
		<link>https://www.alizila.com/ai-powers-1111/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jing Wang]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 07:36:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[11.11]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI Agenda]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alibaba Group]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[11.11 Global Shopping Festival]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alibaba]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[E-Commerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Taobao]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tmall]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.alizila.com/?p=65864</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Kicking off on October 15th 2025, this year’s 11.11 Global Shopping Festival (11.11) marks a pivotal moment. Alibaba is embracing the event as its first large-scale deployment of generative AI in e-commerce, focusing on delivering tangible value for consumers and merchants. One of this year’s key breakthroughs is how Taobao and Tmall have used AI [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Kicking off on October 15<sup>th </sup>2025, this year’s 11.11 Global Shopping Festival (11.11) marks a pivotal moment. Alibaba is embracing the event as its first large-scale deployment of generative AI in e-commerce, focusing on delivering tangible value for consumers and merchants.</p>



<p>One of this year’s key breakthroughs is how Taobao and Tmall have used AI to enrich and index the foundational layer of the e-commerce platforms: a product catalog of over two billion listings. &nbsp;Building on top of this, LLMs have been integrated to core search and recommendation engines. As a result, the search engine can now more comprehensively understand complex contexts in conversation-style queries. In recommendation scenarios, AI leads to more positive surprises in product discovery.</p>



<p>Post-trained on Alibaba’s Qwen large language models, this AI upgrade has led to significant uplift across a number of key metrics &#8211; including a double digit improvement in result relevance for complex queries and a double-digit lift in click-through for certain recommendation scenarios.</p>



<p>&#8220;Our integration of generative AI drove significant improvements on top of an already mature tech stack. We are confident that AI will deliver even greater value across Taobao and Tmall. This includes further gains on core search, recommendation, and advertising engines, empowering the merchants’ day-to-day operations and lowering costs, and exploring new AI native shopping experiences. This year marks the first of many future 11.11s with generative AI deployment at scale,” said Kaifu Zhang, Vice President of Alibaba Group, who heads search, recommendation, and AI innovations at Alibaba’s e-commerce businesses.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" width="1200" height="800" src="https://alizila.oss-us-west-1.aliyuncs.com/uploads/2025/10/凯夫现场图-1.jpg" alt="凯夫现场图 (1)" class="wp-image-65885"/></figure>



<p>Alibaba is transforming its businesses with AI, a strategy backed by its planned US$53 billion investment in AI infrastructure announced in February 2025. While many in the global tech sector are exploring returns on AI investments, Alibaba is seeing early results across its core commerce businesses.</p>



<p><strong>AI Drives E-Commerce Efficiency</strong></p>



<p>AI deployment on Taobao and Tmall this year begins with adding contextual information and indexing to its two billion product listings &#8211; from trending seasonal styles to practical uses for household gadgets. This integration is the foundation for improved search and recommendation, resulting in significantly improved matching precision between products and consumer preferences.</p>



<p>For consumers, the impact is clear. AI-powered recommendations are delivering more relevant and compelling product suggestions in feeds, driving a double-digit uplift in clicks. In search, AI has improved the relevance of results for consumers’ complex queries by 20 percentage points, while also providing contextual recommendations, summarizing reviews, and finding relevant coupons.</p>



<p>On the merchant side, built-in AI capabilities identify marketing opportunities, helping sellers to reach potential consumers more efficiently. The results are powerful: for example, an AI-powered bidding engine drives up marketing ROI by 12%.</p>



<p><strong>An “AI Team” for Millions of Merchants</strong></p>



<p>For the tens of millions of businesses on Taobao and Tmall, Alibaba has upgraded its AI toolkit, creating a virtual “AI team” to help them navigate the busiest season of the year with greater efficiency and cost savings.</p>



<p><em>AIGC Suite Upgraded with Video Generation</em></p>



<p>The upgraded AI-Generated Content (AIGC) suite helps merchants create marketing materials at scale and now includes a new video generation feature. The tool can produce vivid videos from just a few static product photos. Collectively, the AIGC suite generates approximately 200 million images and 5 million videos monthly, driving an over 10% increase in product click-through rates.</p>



<p><em>Proactive Business Insights and Customer Service</em></p>



<p>The AI Business Advisor has evolved from a simple reporting dashboard into a proactive analyst. It generates tailored business recommendations—from dynamic pricing to optimized inventory plans—allowing merchants to act faster. The feature has&nbsp;generated ten million analytical reports for merchants.</p>



<p>The AI-powered customer service assistant “Dianxiaomi” was also upgraded in September 2025, helping merchants save RMB20 million in daily operation costs.</p>



<p><strong>A Smarter Journey for a Billion Shoppers</strong></p>



<p>AI is streamlining the consumer journey on Taobao and Tmall with a set of intelligent tools for a more intuitive shopping experience.</p>



<p>For its more than 53 million 88VIP members, the platform is deploying AI to optimize coupon distributions, better serving this key consumer cohort.</p>



<p><em>From AI Search Bar to Smart Personal Shopper</em></p>



<p>Shoppers can now move beyond simple keywords with conversational search, asking highly specific questions, like “my two-and-a-half-year-old daughter does not like to brush her teeth. What should I buy?”</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" width="1200" height="735" src="https://alizila.oss-us-west-1.aliyuncs.com/uploads/2025/10/Screenshot-2025-10-15-at-8.20.49 PM.png" alt="Screenshot 2025 10 15 At 8.20.49 pm" class="wp-image-65879"/><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">AI search results for children&#8217;s brushing teeth inquiry </figcaption></figure>



<p>An AI Personal Shopping Assistant embedded in the search results and individual product pages acts like a real-life personal shopper, helping customers compare items and find the best deals. For 11.11, the assistant also features <strong>dedicated “AI wish lists”</strong> that provide personalized shopping lists and help consumers navigate the best deals during the festival seamlessly.</p>



<p>Additionally, Taobao and Tmall’s multi-modal search feature, “<em>Snap and shop</em>”, allows consumers to snap a photo and instantly get tiered recommendations by price and quality, helping them make more informed decisions. The AI can intelligently understand and extract text from images—and search using visual and textual cues simultaneously, returning accurate results. A practical use case is helping elderly people understand over-the-counter medicine information on packaging and search for similar products.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" width="852" height="880" src="https://alizila.oss-us-west-1.aliyuncs.com/uploads/2025/10/image.png" alt="Image" class="wp-image-65869"/><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">&#8220;Snap and Shop&#8221; feature</figcaption></figure>



<p><em>AI-Re-imagined</em> <em>Virtual Try-on</em></p>



<p>Virtual try-on technology has received a major AI upgrade, addressing the often-clunky experiences of the past. From just a single photo &#8211; with no special lighting, pose, or setting required &#8211; the system creates a lifelike digital avatar of the consumer with greater consistency. &nbsp;Powered by AI, the system then dresses the avatar with industry-leading remarkable realism, accurately reproducing fabric textures, color gradients, and the natural way materials fold, stretch, and drape.</p>



<p><strong>AI Reimagines E-Commerce</strong></p>



<p>This year’s 11.11 is more than a shopping festival; it is a massive, practical implementation of how AI can be woven into the fabric of e-commerce. By focusing on practical applications that create tangible value, Alibaba demonstrates a future where shopping is more intuitive for consumers and selling is more efficient for businesses of all sizes.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Amap Daily Users Surpass 360 Million as Golden Week Travel Kicks Off</title>
		<link>https://www.alizila.com/amap-daily-users-surpass-360-million-as-golden-week-travel-kicks-off/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jing Wang]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 04:42:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Alibaba Group]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Company News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alibaba]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amap]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chinese Consumers]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.alizila.com/?p=65834</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Driven by its recent AI upgrades, Alibaba’s Amap saw a new peak as daily active users (DAU) surpassed&#160;360&#160;million on October 1, the first day of China’s National Day holidays, setting an all-time high for the platform. Amap’s record performance builds on the strong momentum from its recent launch of an AI-powered ranking, &#8220;Amap Street Stars&#8221;, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Driven by its recent AI upgrades, Alibaba’s Amap saw a new peak as daily active users (DAU) surpassed&nbsp;360&nbsp;million on October 1, the first day of China’s National Day holidays, setting an all-time high for the platform.</p>



<p>Amap’s record performance builds on the strong momentum from its recent launch of an AI-powered ranking, <a href="https://www.alizila.com/amap-street-stars/">&#8220;Amap Street Stars&#8221;</a>, which has rapidly accumulated over 400 million users in less than a month, helping authentic local businesses gain visibility.</p>



<p>The milestones cement Amap’s position as the leading gateway for local lifestyle services in China, guiding users to offline destinations such as tourist attractions, hotels, and restaurants. On October 1 alone, Amap navigated users to more than nine billion kilometers, setting another historical high.</p>



<p>The record was set during China’s “Golden Week” holiday, a peak travel period that is longer than usual this year. Coinciding with the National Day and Mid-Autumn Festival, the eight-day break from October 1 &#8211; 8 is fueling a nationwide surge in travel.</p>



<p>Introduced on September 10, Amap Street Stars has already attracted nearly half of the app’s monthly active users to activate this feature. The rapid growth showcases Amap’s unique value proposition in leveraging AI to solve consumers&#8217; daily-life pain points.</p>



<p>Ahead of the extended holiday, Amap expanded “Street Stars” with a new nationwide&nbsp;‘Top 100 Restaurants’&nbsp;list, covering 45 cities in China to help travelers discover beloved local favorites. The platform saw restaurant daily order volume increase 150% year-over-year on October 1 alone.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&#8220;It’s been incredible. We’re a small, family–run business. Seeing customers traveling great distances just to eat our dishes is truly humbling. Topping this list has brought a level of recognition we never thought possible. We’re thrilled to welcome so many new friends who have made a special trip just to find us,” said Fei Dun, owner of a seafood store in Beihai, a southern coastal City in China.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" width="1200" height="900" src="https://alizila.oss-us-west-1.aliyuncs.com/uploads/2025/10/f8cfd9bc8aa4ac1ed1d0470c85a4b37a.heic.jpg" alt="F8cfd9bc8aa4ac1ed1d0470c85a4b37a.heic" class="wp-image-65854"/></figure>



<p>Photo caption: the local restaurant with Amap Street Stars recognition in Beihai, China</p>



<p>The Golden Week holiday also marked the first wide-scale deployment of Amap’s <a href="https://www.alizila.com/amap-2025/">recently upgraded AI capabilities</a>. The platform’s AI assistant, “Xiaogao”, handled over 2.6 billion user requests on the first day of the holiday, from trip planning to local service recommendations. Through the natural language, conversational interface, “Xiaogao” has recommended over 92 million lifestyle service locations, including restaurants, tourist attractions, and gas stations, boosting the offline consumption traffic.</p>



<p>In parallel, Amap’s AI-powered road safety alert system, “Eagle Eye Guardian”, sent out over 290 million alerts for unusual driving behaviors to help safeguard travelers. Together, these AI features provide users with a safer and more efficient holiday travel experience.</p>



<p>To better support merchant partners, Amap also recently announced a one-year annual fee exemption for restaurants. This initiative and other support measures, like offline spending subsidies, have led to significant growth in the number of new restaurant merchants joining.</p>



<p><em><br></em>The new user records are a clear validation of Amap’s recent, AI-driven transformation and evolution into an essential tool for local lifestyle services. This proven performance solidifies Amap’s role as a critical pillar in Alibaba’s strategy to build a comprehensive consumption platform that serves the diverse, daily life needs of its users.<br><br>(The story was updated on October 3rd)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Alibaba Cloud’s Apsara Conference 2025: Full Stack AI + Cloud Leads the Way to the Future of AI</title>
		<link>https://www.alizila.com/alibaba-clouds-apsara-conference-2025-full-stack-ai-cloud-leads-the-way-to-the-future-of-ai/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Shao Xiaoyi]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 27 Sep 2025 05:29:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apsara Conference]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.alizila.com/?p=65821</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[At Apsara 2025, Alibaba Cloud unveiled its global AI roadmap, announcing plans to increase investment beyond its previously disclosed three-year RMB 380 billion (US$53 billion) AI infrastructure program, alongside a global expansion strategy, its most powerful AI models to date, and upgrades across its cloud portfolio. Eddie Wu, Chairman and CEO of Alibaba Cloud Intelligence, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>At Apsara 2025, Alibaba Cloud unveiled its global AI roadmap, announcing plans to increase investment beyond its previously disclosed three-year RMB 380 billion (US$53 billion) AI infrastructure program, alongside a global expansion strategy, its most powerful AI models to date, and upgrades across its cloud portfolio.</p>



<p>Eddie Wu, Chairman and CEO of Alibaba Cloud Intelligence, called the move a defining moment: “Alibaba Cloud is strategically positioned as a full-stack AI service provider, dedicated to delivering robust computing with maximized efficiency for training and deploying large AI models on the cloud. To underscore our long-term commitment to advancing AI, we will progress with our RMB 380 billion investment plan in AI and cloud infrastructure over the next three years.”</p>



<p>“We remain committed to open-sourcing Qwen and shaping it into the ‘operating system of the AI era,’ empowering developers around the world to build transformative AI applications.”</p>



<p>Here’s why these announcements matter — and how they could reshape the industry landscape.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" width="1200" height="651" src="https://alizila.oss-us-west-1.aliyuncs.com/uploads/2025/09/A15358E3-55BD-46DC-BBFC-F670625F462F-66624-0000333D298BF4EB.png" alt="A15358e3 55bd 46dc Bbfc F670625f462f 66624 0000333d298bf4eb" class="wp-image-65807"/></figure>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-qwen3-max-a-trillion-parameter-flagship-model"><a></a><strong>Qwen3-Max: A trillion-parameter flagship model</strong></h3>



<p>During Alibaba Cloud’s annual flagship technology conference, Alibaba Cloud introduced a series of new large language models from Qwen3 family, headlined by <a href="https://qwen.ai/blog%20id=241398b9cd6353de490b0f82806c7848c5d2777d&amp;from=research.latest-advancements-list?spm=a3c0i.33193755.2701136720.2.5c6f1228xJsZCl&amp;file=blog%20id=241398b9cd6353de490b0f82806c7848c5d2777d&amp;from=research.latest-advancements-list">Qwen3-Max</a> and previewed its latest visual-generation models.</p>



<p><strong>At the center of the announcements was Qwen3-Max</strong>, Alibaba’s largest LLM model and the most powerful LLMs to date, is a trillion-parameter model designed for businesses and developers. It achieves impressive performance across a wide range of benchmarks especially in code generation and agentic capabilities.</p>



<p><strong>Complementing this flagship model is Qwen3-Omni</strong>, a multilingual omni-model capable of processing text, images, audio, and video inputs, while delivering real-time, streaming response in text and speech.&nbsp;By achieving real-time multimodal interaction, with ultra-low latency, it is an ideal solution for intuitive, hands-free interaction in intelligent cockpits, smart glasses and mobile phones.</p>



<p>Alibaba also broadened its portfolio with several new domain-specific models, including <strong>Qwen3-VL</strong>, a vision-language model optimal for robotics and navigation; an upgraded <strong>Qwen3-Coder</strong> for faster and more accurate code generation; <strong>Qwen3-Image-Edit</strong>, which now supports editing multiple images with improved visual consistency; and <strong>Wan2.5 Preview</strong>, the latest visual generation model designed to elevate multimedia content creation.</p>



<p>Enterprises can access and deploy these models through Model Studio, Alibaba’s AI development platform. The newly-upgraded Model Studio features a high-code agent development framework <strong>Model Studio-ADK</strong> (agent development kits) to help enterprises enhance agent development efficiency. It also introduces a range of enterprise-grade features, including seamless connectivity via Model Context Protocol (MCP), RAG multi-modal fusion, dynamic inference scheduling, and sandbox service, to address key enterprise challenges such as multi-source data processing, resource constraints, and cross-environment deployment.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" width="1200" height="800" src="https://alizila.oss-us-west-1.aliyuncs.com/uploads/2025/09/TAOL5677-opq3990635504.jpg" alt="Taol5677 Opq3990635504" class="wp-image-65813"/></figure>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-upgrading-the-cloud-for-ai-at-scale"><a></a><strong>Upgrading the cloud for AI at scale</strong></h3>



<p>To support trillion-parameter models at scale, Alibaba Cloud has undertaken a sweeping overhaul of its infrastructure, with a focus on speed, scalability, and security.</p>



<p>At the core of these upgrades is the new HPN8.0 network, which delivers up to 800 Gbps throughput—twice the capacity of the previous generation, ensuring faster, more reliable data transfer for AI workloads. Storage has also been reimagined through Vector Bucket technology, which integrates raw and vector data to enable real-time search and retrieval-augmented generation (RAG) pipelines.</p>



<p>Database performance is being pushed further with PolarDB database powered by Compute Express Link (CXL) technology, delivering 72% lower latency and sixteen times greater scalability; The upgraded Alibaba Cloud Container Compute Service (ACS) is capable of scaling up to 15,000 pods per minute, providing the elasticity required for enterprise-grade deployments.</p>



<p>Security has also been strengthened through enhancements to the Cloud Threat Detection and Response (CTDR) solution, which now leverages five Qwen-powered agents to raise boost investigation accuracy from 59% to 74% while and automating 70% of incident responses.</p>



<p>Looking beyond its core infrastructure, Alibaba Cloud is also expanding its global footprint. The company announced plans to open first data centers in Brazil, France, and the Netherlands, along with upcoming facilities in Mexico, Japan, South Korea, Malaysia and Dubai in the coming year.</p>



<p>Two newly added service centers in Germany and Indonesia will further extend its reach, supporting international customers with round-the-clock, multi-language services.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-growing-base-of-real-world-users"><a></a><strong>Growing base of real-world users</strong></h3>



<p>Alibaba Cloud isn’t starting from scratch. Earlier versions of Qwen and Wan are already in use across a diverse range of sectors, proving Alibaba Cloud ’s stack can handle real-world enterprise workloads.</p>



<p>To date, Alibaba has reported <strong>over 600 million model downloads</strong> of its Qwen and Wan series, approximately <strong>170,000 derivative models</strong>, and more than <strong>800,000 AI agents</strong> built on Model Studio, as well as over one million corporates and individuals using Qwen through Model Studio, forming a solid base for Qwen3’s rollout.</p>



<p>The technology is already making an impact in key sectors. In healthcare, <strong>AstraZeneca</strong> <strong>China</strong> uses a Qwen-based model to detect and summarize adverse drug events with 95% accuracy, delivering a threefold&nbsp; efficiency gain.</p>



<p>In financial services, a Tokyo-based AI startup, <strong>FLUX</strong><strong> </strong>has developed a 32billionparameter Japanese language model designed specifically for the industry, giving professionals more reliable, context-aware responses to industry-specific queries.,</p>



<p>In digital marketing, <strong>GladCube</strong> has partnered with Alibaba Cloud to integrate Alibaba’s visual generation model, Wan, into its vertical video transformation platform “Dra&nbsp;Vis”, enabling Japanese customers to produce high-quality video, content quickly and at scale, enhancing both efficiency and creativity.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" width="1200" height="800" src="https://alizila.oss-us-west-1.aliyuncs.com/uploads/2025/09/AFA02769-opq3988371645.jpg" alt="Afa02769 Opq3988371645" class="wp-image-65812"/></figure>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-laying-the-groundwork-for-the-future"><a></a><strong>Laying the groundwork for the future</strong></h3>



<p>Alibaba Cloud is now turning its attention to Physical AI systems where AI not only processes data but also takes action in the physical world, from robots, and autonomous vehicles, to industrial machinery.</p>



<p>A key step in this direction is the integration of the full suite of the NVIDIA Physical AI software stack, into Alibaba Cloud’s Platform for AI (PAI), marking a milestone collaboration in the Physical AI domain. The initiative provides developers with a comprehensive, cloud-native platform to accelerate advancements in Physical AI solutions.</p>



<p>Looking ahead, Alibaba Cloud envisions a future where large AI models are deeply embedded across devices, functioning much like operating systems with persistent memory, seamless coordination between cloud and edge, and the capacity to continuously evolve.</p>



<p>With its foundation models, upgraded infrastructure, and expanding global network, Alibaba Cloud has assembled the full-stack building blocks that allow organizations around the world to build, deploy, and govern AI on their own terms.</p>



<p><em>Explore comprehensive details about the Apsara Conference 2025 at <a href="https://www.alizila.com/media-resource/apsara-conference-2025-press-kit/">Apsara Conference 2025: Press Kit</a></em></p>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Alibaba Continues IPR Leadership Across East and Southeast Asia</title>
		<link>https://www.alizila.com/alibaba-continues-ipr-leadership-across-east-and-southeast-asia/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alizila Staff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 07:34:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Alibaba Group]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Company News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.alizila.com/?p=65777</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[With a series of events and strategic partnerships, Alibaba continues to deepen its intellectual property rights (IPR) engagement in the Asia Pacific region. Recent activities led by the Alibaba International’s Global IP Enforcement team along with the Lazada and AliExpress Korea platforms signal growing recognition of Alibaba’s IPR initiatives across key markets in the region. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>With a series of events and strategic partnerships, Alibaba continues to deepen its intellectual property rights (IPR) engagement in the Asia Pacific region. Recent activities led by the Alibaba International’s Global IP Enforcement team along with the Lazada and AliExpress Korea platforms signal growing recognition of Alibaba’s IPR initiatives across key markets in the region.</p>



<p><strong>E-Commerce Roundtable in Bangkok Draws Official Praise</strong></p>



<p>One notable highlight was the <em>E-Commerce Platform Roundtable Discussion</em> hosted on July 16 at the Lazada Thailand office. Led and hosted by Alibaba, the event convened over 80 participants, including senior officials from the Thailand’s Department of Intellectual Property (DIP), Royal Thai Police’s Economic Crime Suppression Division (ECD), the US Patent and Trademark Office (USPTO), and Korea Intellectual Property Protection Agency (KOIPA).</p>



<p>Thailand DIP’s Deputy Director General, Mr. Arwut Wongsawas, recognized Alibaba in his keynote remarks, “I would like to commend the commitment of Lazada and Alibaba in recognizing the importance of intellectual property protection, and in organizing and hosting today’s e-commerce round table discussion which provides a forum for exchanging ideas on IP protection and collaboratively discussing e-commerce practices to provide reliable, safe and fair practices.&#8221; The event earned strong acclaim, including by the USPTO’s Sr. IP Specialist Chanchart Chotiphol, who delivered the closing remarks and further underscored the event&#8217;s strategic importance.</p>



<p>Representatives from international IPR organizations such as the International Trademark Association (INTA) and React – The Anti-Counterfeiting Network (React), Asia Pacific, also joined the discussions reflecting Alibaba’s role as a facilitator of regional cooperation on IPR issues.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" width="1200" height="800" src="https://alizila.oss-us-west-1.aliyuncs.com/uploads/2025/09/3334b3709e5c4ef8bc226e09b5c6a09b.jpg" alt="3334b3709e5c4ef8bc226e09b5c6a09b" class="wp-image-65802"/><figcaption class="wp-element-caption"><em>Joyce Ang and Daniel Dougherty from Alibaba&#8217;s Global IP Enforcement team with Thailand DIP, ECD, and USPTO, along with attendees of the E-Commerce Platform Roundtable Discussion</em></figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>AliExpress to Innovate IPR Protection in Korea</strong><strong></strong></p>



<p>Also in July, AliExpress Korea signed a landmark Memorandum of Understanding (MoU) with the Trade-related IPR Protection Association (TIPA) to strengthen IPR protection in cross-border trade. The announcement of the joint effort can be found <a href="https://www.news1.kr/industry/general-industry/5843102">here</a>. Through this partnership, AliExpress became the first e-commerce platform to proactively work with TIPA to utilize its customs seizure information in order to enhance IPR enforcement and protection for both brands and consumers.</p>



<p>Daniel Dougherty, Senior Director of Alibaba International, said, &#8220;Our close cooperation with TIPA will strengthen efforts to protect both IP and consumers. AliExpress and Alibaba are pleased to continue to lead in IP protection efforts.&#8221; TIPA President Nam-gi Chung added, “This meaningful collaboration will significantly strengthen the IPR protection ecosystem and serve as a milestone for IP protection in the e-commerce sector.”</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" width="1200" height="800" src="https://alizila.oss-us-west-1.aliyuncs.com/uploads/2025/09/IMG_0391.jpg" alt="Img 0391" class="wp-image-65799"/><figcaption class="wp-element-caption"><em>Nam-gi Chung and Hyuk-kyu Kwon from TIPA, together with Daniel Dougherty and Mizi Park from Alibaba&#8217;s Global IP Enforcement team at the MoU signing ceremony</em></figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>Strengthening IPR Protection for K-beauty Brands</strong><strong></strong></p>



<p>Alibaba is also working closely with key industries to strengthen IPR protection. On June 17, Alibaba International and AliExpress Korea partnered with the Korea Cosmetic Association (KCA) to co-host the <em>K-Beauty Business &amp; IP Strategy Conference</em> in Seoul. The event brought together over 50 Korean industry participants for a day of exchange and insight into Alibaba’s IPR protection mechanisms and emerging e-commerce trends in the beauty industry.</p>



<p>Ray Zhang, CEO of AliExpress Korea, opened the event, followed by presentations from Alibaba’s Global IP Enforcement team, and AliExpress Korea and Lazada business representatives from the be cosmetics sector. One attendee noting, “We learned through this conference that Alibaba has a deep understanding of and genuine interest in the beauty sector.”</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" width="1200" height="895" src="https://alizila.oss-us-west-1.aliyuncs.com/uploads/2025/09/20250811_143542.jpg" alt="20250811 143542" class="wp-image-65798"/><figcaption class="wp-element-caption"><em>Mizi Park from Alibaba&#8217;s Global IP Enforcement and Ray Zhang, CEO of AliExpress Korea, speaking at the K-Beauty Business &amp; IP Strategy Conference</em></figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>Activating the Next Generation of IP Advocates</strong><strong></strong></p>



<p>To promote public education and IP awareness, Alibaba and AliExpress Korea partnered with Hongik University, Korea’s leading design school, to hold a student design competition. The competition encouraged students to creatively express the importance of IPR protection and helped promote awareness of IP issues through the lens of young designers.</p>



<p>The top honor, the <em>Global Intellectual Property Award</em>, was awarded to the slogan: <em>Fake? Can’t Relate</em>, which was uniformly embraced by Alibaba, Hongik University and the judges from the Korea Intellectual Property Protection Agency (KOIPA), Korea Intellectual Property Association (KINPA), and the Korea Fashion Association’s Fashion IP Center for its firm rejection of counterfeit culture through Gen Z’s own voice. Professor Hyunju Park of Hongik University remarked, “This partnership with Alibaba International, which brings strong expertise in IPR protection, greatly enhanced the educational impact of the program.”</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" width="1200" height="823" src="https://alizila.oss-us-west-1.aliyuncs.com/uploads/2025/09/c58c3bb1fee442698f54e9f36de020b4.jpg" alt="C58c3bb1fee442698f54e9f36de020b4" class="wp-image-65797"/><figcaption class="wp-element-caption"><em>Daniel Dougherty and Mizi Park from Alibaba’s Global IP Enforcement team, together with award winners, and administrators and faculty members of Hongik University, at the award ceremony</em></figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>Empowering Small, and Medium-Sized Enterprises (SMEs)</strong></p>



<p>Alibaba International also introduced dedicated <a href="https://ipp.aidcgroup.net/#/smeHome">SME resources</a> within its IPP Platform this summer. The SME content offers a wealth of IPR-related information including the basics of IPR, why IPR is important, and information about obtaining IPR protection. Also included are links to additional IPR resources such as national, regional and international IPR offices. With these resources, Alibaba is helping small businesses secure their innovations, build strong brands, and sustain their long-term growth in a fiercely competitive digital environment. To best position SMEs for success, the resources are available in seven languages from the Asia Pacific region.</p>



<p>Additionally, Alibaba International recently upgraded its <a href="https://ipp.aidcgroup.net/#/articles">FAQ content</a> on the IPP Platform to further support SMEs, and other rights holders, by providing the most current information on commonly encountered IPR enforcement questions.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" width="1200" height="368" src="https://alizila.oss-us-west-1.aliyuncs.com/uploads/2025/09/image-8.png" alt="Image" class="wp-image-65791"/></figure>



<p><strong>Singapore – Intellectual Property in Trade and Digital Commerce</strong></p>



<p>On August 28, Alibaba International co<strong>&#8211;</strong>hosted <a href="https://site.smu.edu.sg/intellectual-property-trade-and-digital-commerce#home">a high-level IPR seminar</a> in Singapore alongside the U.S.-based McCarthy Institute and the Singapore Management University (SMU), Centre for Digital Law. An associated event of IP Week @ Singapore, the event, titled <em>Intellectual Property in Trade and Digital Commerce</em>, convened leading voices from the IPR community, including policy makers, industry stakeholders, and academia to explore key IPR themes such as the complexities of AI litigation, innovative approaches to IPR dispute resolution, and support for SMEs.</p>



<p>Speakers for the event included SMU School of Law Dean Lee Pey Woan, who delivered welcome remarks, a keynote address by Mr. Daren Tang, Director General of the World Intellectual Property Organization (WIPO), and panel discussions with industry experts such as Attorney Brigitte M. da Costa-Villaluz, Director General of the Intellectual Property Office of the Philippines (IPOPHL), and representatives from IPOS and Thailand DIP. Another highlight of this day-long event was a fireside chat featuring the Southeast Asia-based IP Attachés from the UK, France and U.S.</p>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Alibaba Recognized on Fortune&#8217;s 2025 Change the World List for Open-Source AI</title>
		<link>https://www.alizila.com/alibaba-recognized-on-fortunes-2025-change-the-world-list-for-open-source-ai/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alizila Staff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 01:58:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alibaba Group]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Company News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.alizila.com/?p=65746</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Fortune’s 2025 Change the World List has recognized Alibaba’s pioneering open-source commitment to making artificial intelligence accessible to developers, researchers and businesses worldwide. Alibaba’s 2025 recognition marks the most appearances by a Chinese tech company on the Change the World List, which spotlights companies that create a positive impact at scale through their core business [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Fortune’s 2025 <a href="https://fortune.com/ranking/change-the-world/">Change the World List</a> has recognized Alibaba’s pioneering open-source commitment to making artificial intelligence accessible to developers, researchers and businesses worldwide. Alibaba’s 2025 recognition marks the most appearances by a Chinese tech company on the Change the World List, which spotlights companies that create a positive impact at scale through their core business operations.</p>



<p>Alibaba stands out for its bold decision to open-source its Qwen family of over 300 generative AI models, a strategy that runs counter to keeping advanced AI technologies proprietary.</p>



<p>In its citation, Fortune editors noted Alibaba’s contribution to economic empowerment recognizing that its open-source models are now among the most widely used worldwide. “By releasing AI models under an open-source model, either for free or at low rates, Alibaba is empowering startups, researchers, and hobbyists to experiment with this new technology without shelling out for expensive licensing fees. Chinese AI developers like Alibaba have now changed the conversation around AI, pushing U.S.-based competitors like OpenAI and xAI to release their own open-source models.”</p>



<p>The recognition centers on Alibaba&#8217;s Qwen series of large language models, first open-sourced in August 2023. Alibaba was one of the earliest major tech firms to make high-performing AI models freely available. Since then, the Qwen family has achieved significant global adoption, with over 600 million downloads and more than 170,000 derivative models created by developers worldwide. Over 1 million corporate and individual users have used Qwen on Model Studio, Alibaba&#8217;s AI development platform, since its launch.</p>



<p>Alibaba Group CEO Eddie Wu reinforced the company’s commitment to open source at its Apsara Conference&nbsp;2025, the Group’s annual flagship technology conference on Wednesday in Hangzhou. “We remain committed to open-sourcing Qwen and shaping it into the ‘operating system of the AI era,’ empowering developers around the world to build transformative AI applications. &#8220;</p>



<p><strong>A “Game Changer” for AI Adoption </strong></p>



<p>Alibaba Group Chairman Joe Tsai previously articulated the company’s vision for open source, stating that it will be a <a href="https://www.alizila.com/alibaba-chairman-joe-tsai-on-ai-open-source-proliferates-application-and-use-case/">“game changer”</a> to proliferate applications and innovation.</p>



<p>Alibaba&#8217;s open-source strategy directly addresses what many consider one of technology&#8217;s most pressing challenges: access to powerful AI tools. By supporting 119 languages and dialects, Qwen models have enabled innovation in underserved markets where expensive usage fees for closed-source models would otherwise create barriers to entry.</p>



<p>Startups around the world are already making an impact with Alibaba’s open-source models. For example, by using Qwen’s models, the 15-person Korean agentic AI startup Univa avoided expensive licensing fees and reduced costs by 30%. “Without Qwen’s open-source alternative to the leading close-source models, we would not have been able to compete with larger companies”, said Nam MyungJin, CEO of Univa.</p>



<p>Meanwhile, Oxford University spinout OxValue.AI used Qwen’s multimodal models to deliver affordable, accurate company valuations in minutes. “Alibaba was the earliest leading company to open-source multimodal models and continued to improve its computing speed, which significantly expanded the information input and efficiency for company valuations”, said Xiong Peng, CEO of OxValue.AI.</p>



<p>To support its unwavering commitment to advancing AI technology, Alibaba announced in February a three-year $53 billion investment in cloud computing and AI infrastructure. The company is actively proceeding with these investments and planning to invest more.</p>



<p>Beyond individual success stories, Alibaba has fostered an ecosystem through ModelScope, China&#8217;s largest open-source AI community. The platform now serves over 18 million users and hosts 100,000 models, demonstrating the scale of Alibaba&#8217;s influence.</p>



<p>Researchers from academic institutions have embraced the accessibility of Qwen models, achieving breakthrough results that would have been prohibitively expensive with proprietary alternatives. Stanford University and the University of Washington used Qwen to develop their own top-performing models at a cost of under $50. UC Berkeley&#8217;s team trained an RL-based math model for under $30.</p>



<p>The company&#8217;s commitment extends beyond technology to education and collaboration. From hackathons in Singapore and Malaysia to partnerships with the International Telecommunication Union and participation in the UN&#8217;s AI Skills Coalition, Alibaba is actively working to ensure the benefits of AI reach underserved communities worldwide.</p>



<p><strong>AI-driven Strategy Yielded Solid Progress</strong></p>



<p>Fortune editors also noted that bridging the digital divide could be good for Alibaba’s business prospects. “Developers trained on Qwen will likely join Alibaba’s cloud ecosystem, an increasingly lucrative business for the tech company,” the magazine wrote.</p>



<p>Guided by a group-wide AI-driven strategy, the company&#8217;s &#8220;AI+ Cloud&#8221; value proposition has become increasingly compelling for enterprise clients. AI has emerged as a growth engine for Alibaba’s cloud business. In the quarter ending June 2025, cloud revenue grew 26% year-over-year, with AI-related revenue accounting for over 20% of revenue from external customers and continuing to grow at triple digits for the eighth consecutive quarter.</p>



<p>&#8220;The transformative impact of AI on all industries, combined with the deep integration of AI and cloud, will present the most significant opportunity in the technology sector over the next decade.&nbsp;For Alibaba, we have the world’s fourth-largest and Asia’s leading cloud infrastructure, along with full-stack technology capabilities spanning AI computing power, AI cloud platforms, AI models, an open-source ecosystem, and AI applications,&#8221; said Eddie Wu in the latest <a href="https://www.alizila.com/aliviews-eddie-wu-on-alibabas-fy26q1-earnings/">June quarter earnings call</a>, outlining how Alibaba is well positioned to capture AI opportunities.</p>



<p>As AI continues to reshape industries and societies, Alibaba&#8217;s inclusion on Fortune&#8217;s Change the World list validates an approach that prioritizes accessibility alongside advancement. Alibaba&#8217;s commitment to open-source represents a distinct path forward in the AI era.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
